<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newtech on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/tags/newtech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Newtech on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 22:40:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/tags/newtech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The MAKOplasty Procedure</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/makoplasty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 22:40:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/makoplasty/</guid>
      <description>What is MAKOplasty&amp;reg;? MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Partial Knee Resurfacing and MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Total Hip Replacement are enabled by the surgeon controlled RIO® robotic arm system, offering increased accuracy to optimize surgical results.
MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Partial Knee Resurfacing Partial Knee Replacement is a treatment option for adults living with early-to mid-stage osteoarthritis (OA) that has not progressed to all three compartments of the knee. MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Partial Knee Resurfacing is an advanced treatment option. It is powered by the RIO® Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System, which allows the surgeon to perform surgery accurately through a smaller incision as compared to manual procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRP Injections</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/prp-injections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 23:11:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/prp-injections/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Thomas Myers is now offering PRP injections in the office Platelet Rich Plasma injections are a new technology that uses natural healing factors to treat chronic injuries.
PRP injections are most commonly used for tendonitis or chronic injuries such as:
 Tennis/Golfer’s Elbow aka Lateral/Medial Epicondylitis Achilles Tendonitis Plantar Fasciitis Chronic Hamstring Strains Runner’s Knee aka Patellar Tendonitis Other uses can be discussed with the physician as indicated, however these are the most common at this time</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>