<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Knee on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Knee on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:41:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of an ACL Tear</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:52:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</guid>
      <description>The anterior cruciate ligament, also known as the ACL, is one of the major cruciate ligaments that are located within the joints of the knee. The ACL provides stability to your knees, along with preventing over-bending and over-straightening of the knee. The ligament is connected between the tibia and femur. A torn ACL can refer to any injury caused to the ligament. A number of different things can cause a town ACL, such as a twisting force applied to the knee while the foot is firmly placed on the ground, or a direct blow to the knee upon a landing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meniscus Tears</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:47:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</guid>
      <description>The meniscus is a small, “c” shaped piece of cartilage that acts as a cushion for the knee joint. They sit between the shin bone (tibia) and the thigh bone (femur), with one being on the outside and one being on the inside of the knee.
What Is a Meniscus Tear? A meniscus tear usually occurs during movements that forcefully rotate the knee while the knee is bearing weight, which results in the piece of cartilage being torn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articular Cartilage Tear Information</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:44:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</guid>
      <description>What is articular cartilage? Articular cartilage, also known as hyaline cartilage, is a very smooth yet hard material made up of the protein collagen. The cartilage is located on a bone’s articulating surfaces (surfaces of a bone that come in contact with other bones). It allows for the smooth interaction between two bones in a joint.
How does articular cartilage get injured? Damage can result in the articular cartilage as an isolated incident or occur due to another knee injury.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>