<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Knee on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>http://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Knee on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:41:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of an ACL Tear</title>
      <link>http://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:52:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</guid>
      <description>The anterior cruciate ligament, also known as the ACL, is one of the major ligaments within the knee joint. The ligament connects the femur and tibia bones, providing stability to the knee and preventing over-bending and over-straightening. An ACL tear can refer to any injury caused to the ligament, from a minor sprain to a true tear.  
ACL tears are one of the most common types of sports injuries, and are typically caused by motions that apply twisting forces on the knee such as pivoting one one foot or stopping suddenly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meniscus Tears</title>
      <link>http://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:47:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</guid>
      <description>The menisci are small, “C”-shaped pieces of cartilage that act as cushions for the knee joint. Each knee has both a medial (inner, towards the midline of the body) and lateral (outer) meniscus, both sitting on top of the tibia (shin bone). How does a Meniscus Become Torn?  A meniscus tear usually occurs during movements that forcefully rotate the knee while the knee is bearing weight, which results in the piece of cartilage being torn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articular Cartilage Tear Information</title>
      <link>http://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:44:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</guid>
      <description>What is articular cartilage?  Articular cartilage, also known as hyaline cartilage, is a very smooth yet hard material made up of the protein collagen. The cartilage is located on a bone’s articulating surfaces (surfaces of a bone that come in contact with other bones). It allows for the smooth interaction between two bones in joints such as the knee.
 
How does articular cartilage get injured?  Damage to the articular cartilage may occur as an isolated incident or may develop due to another knee injury.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>