<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Shoulder on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Shoulder on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:56:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adhesive Capsulitis</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:17:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</guid>
      <description>Adhesive capsulitis of the shoulder is characterized by a reduction in shoulder range of motion and pain with movement. This condition is commonly referred to as frozen shoulder, as the shoulder usually becomes &amp;ldquo;frozen&amp;rdquo; in place and may become difficult to move at all. The causes of adhesive capsulitis are somewhat unknown and the condition tends to develop without a specfic mechanism of injury.

What are the Symptoms of Adhesive Capsulitis?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slap Tears</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:15:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</guid>
      <description>A SLAP tear, also known as a superior labral tear, occurs when part of the shoulder joint known as the labrum is torn. The shoulder is similar to the hip in that they are both ball and socket joints, but the shoulder joint is considerably more shallow and less stable as a result. The labrum helps overcome this instability by forming a &amp;ldquo;cup&amp;rdquo; that surrounds the head of the humerus and provides additional support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labral Tears</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:11:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</guid>
      <description>The shoulder joint is similar to the hip as they are both ball and socket joints. However, the shoulder joint’s socket is more shallow, which makes it inherently less stable. This means that extra support is needed to adequately hold the shoulder bones in place.

 
To compensate for this shallow socket, the shoulder has a cuff of cartilage known as the labrum surrounding its joint. The labrum forms a cup for the end of the arm bone (the humerus) to move around in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Frozen Shoulder?</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:06:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</guid>
      <description>Frozen shoulder, also known as adhesive capsulitis, is characterized by pain and restriction of motion in the shoulder joint. Normally, the shoulder allows a greater range of motion than any other joint in the body. However, in patients with a frozen shoulder, the capsule around the shoulder joint contracts, forming bands of scar tissue (adhesions). These adhesions &#34;freeze&#34; the head of the humerus (upper arm bone) in place, causing pain and restricting movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of a Dislocated Shoulder</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:04:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</guid>
      <description>Shoulder dislocation is a relatively common injury in a wide variety of sports. Generally, when a shoulder is dislocated, the head of the humerus (the upper arm bone) is forced forwards when the arm is turned outwards and being held out to the side. This dislocation, known as an anterior dislocation, makes up approximately 95% of all shoulder dislocations.
 Posterior are the second most common type of dislocation with 3% or dislocations being posterior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of a Rotator Cuff Tear</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</guid>
      <description>The rotator cuff is a group of muscles and tendons that are responsible for the glenohumeral (shoulder) joint’s stability while it moves and rotates. The rotator cuff includes the Supraspinatus, Infraspinatus, Teres Minor, and the Subscapularis muscles as well as their associated tendons. Of these, the supraspinatus and infraspinatus tendons are the most commonly injured. When healthy, these tissues surround the shoulder joint and keep the head of the humerus (upper arm bone) in place during movement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>