<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Shoulder on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Shoulder on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:56:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adhesive Capsulitis</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:17:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</guid>
      <description>Adhesive capsulitis is when a person loses the ability to move their shoulder around in all directions without pain. This problem is commonly referred to as a frozen shoulder, as the shoulder usually becomes stiff and will be hard to move at all. The causes of ashesive capsulitis are somewhat unknown and tend to happen randomly.
What are the Symptoms of Adhesive Capsulitis? A shoulder should be able to move in all directions without any stiffness or pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slap Tears</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:15:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</guid>
      <description>A SLAP tear, also known as a superior labral tear, is when part of the shoulder joint known as the labrum is torn. The shoulder is similar to the hip as they are both ball and socket joints, but the shoulder joint is very shallow, so it is unstable. The labrum helps make the shoulder more stable by forming a cup that the end of the humerus can move around in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labral Tears</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:11:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</guid>
      <description>The shoulder joint is similar to the hip as they are both ball and socket joints. The shoulder joint’s socket is very shallow though, which inherently makes the shoulder joint unstable. This means that extra support in the shoulder is needed as the shoulder bones aren’t held in place adequately.shoulder-labrum-tear
 The labrum is what compensates for the shallow socket the shoulder joint has. The labrum is a cuff of cartilage that forms a cup for the end of the arm bone (the humerus) to move around in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frozen Shoulder Symptoms</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:08:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>A frozen shoulder causes symptoms easily recognizable by a doctor. The most noticeable symptom is restricted movement in the shoulder. It is possible for other conditions to have similar symptoms as a frozen shoulder, such as a rotator cuff tear, so always have your medical problem diagnosed properly by a doctor. There are different causes of frozen shoulders.
Common Frozen Shoulder Symptoms:  Limited and restricted movement of the shoulder Shoulder pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Frozen Shoulder?</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:06:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</guid>
      <description>A frozen shoulder, also known as adhesive capsulitis, is when motion of the shoulder joint is restricted. The cause of frozen shoulders isn’t well understood, and it usually happens randomly for no known reason. A frozen will cause the capsule around the shoulder joint to contract, which forms scar tissue.
Causes of a Frozen Shoulder Generally, a frozen shoulder will occur without an associated injury or cause. It’s possible for a patient to develop a frozen shoulder after some sort of injury, but that is usually not the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of a Dislocated Shoulder</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:04:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</guid>
      <description>Shoulder dislocation is a common injury that usually results from a wide variety of sports. Generally when a shoulder is dislocated, the head of the humerus (the upper arm bone) is forced forwards when the arm is turned outwards and being held out to the side. This dislocation, known as an anterior dislocation, makes up approximately 95% of all shoulder dislocations.
 The other 5% of dislocations, posterior dislocations, inferior dislocations, superior dislocations, or intra thoracic dislocations, are rarer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of a Rotator Cuff Tear</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</guid>
      <description>The rotator cuff is a group of muscles which work together and are responsible for the shoulder (Glenohumeral) joint’s stability while it moves and rotates. The rotator cuff muscles include Supraspinatus, Infraspinatus, Teres Minor, and the Subscapularis.
The Supraspinatus and Infraspinatus are the most commonly injured rotator cuff muscles. These injuries are usually related to sports involved with a lot of shoulder rotation, such as swimming, pitching a baseball, or bowling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>