<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:16:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cigna</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/insurance/cigna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:16:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/insurance/cigna/</guid>
      <description>CIGNA is a global health service company, dedicated to helping people improve their health, well-being and security. We provide an integrated suite of health, life, accident, disability and other wellness benefits to groups and individuals, serving over 45 million people throughout the United States and around the world.
Dr. Myers accepts CIGNA as a form of health insurance.
Cigna Homepage
Information taken from cigna.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United Health Care</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/insurance/united-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 23:57:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/insurance/united-health-care/</guid>
      <description>UnitedHealthcare is an operating division of UnitedHealth Group, the largest single health carrier in the United States.
As a recognized leader in the health and well-being industry, United Health Care strives to: * Improve the quality and effectiveness of health care for all Americans * Enhance access to health benefits * Create products and services that make health care more affordable * Use technology to make the health care system easier to navigate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aetna</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/insurance/aetna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:17:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/insurance/aetna/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Myers accepts Aetna as a form of health insurance.
Aetna offers “offer a broad range of traditional and consumer-directed health insurance products and related services. These include medical, pharmacy, dental, behavioral health, group life, long-term care and disability plans and medical management capabilities. Our customers include employer groups, individuals, college students, part-time and hourly workers, health plans and government-sponsored plans.”
Dr. Myers accepts Aetna as a form of health insurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Cross Blue Shield</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/insurance/blue-cross-blue-shield/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:08:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/insurance/blue-cross-blue-shield/</guid>
      <description>One of the most trusted names in health coverage, Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Georgia has been providing quality health benefits to state residents for over 70 years.
Dr. Myers accepts Blue Cross Blue Shield as a form of health insurance.
Blue Cross Blue Shield Homepage
Blue Cross Blue Shield Georgia Homepage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concierge Service</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/patient-info/concierge-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/patient-info/concierge-service/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/about/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/about/contact-us/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Information</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/dr-myers/key-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/dr-myers/key-information/</guid>
      <description>Specialties Open &amp;amp; Arthroscopic Cartilage Replacement Procedures Knee and Shoulder Arthroscopy Sports Injuries – ACL Reconstruction
Board Certification American Board of Orthopaedic Surgery
ABOS Subspecialty Certification in Sports Medicine
Hospital Affiliations St. Joseph’s Hospital Atlanta Outpatient Surgery Center Piedmont West Outpatient Surgery Center
Fellowships Sports Medicine American Sports Medicine Institute Birmingham, Alabama
Orthopaedic Trauma Harvard School of Medicine Boston, MA
Postgraduate Training Orthopaedic Residency Harvard School of Medicine Boston, MA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kristiann Settles</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/kristiann-settles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/kristiann-settles/</guid>
      <description>Kristiann Settles obtained her Bachelor of Science in Exercise &amp;amp; Health Science from Kennesaw State University in 2014. Early in her studies, Kristiann conducted an analysis in Biomechanics, which stimulated an interest in orthopaedic rehabilitation and encouraged her to assist in rehabilitating a variety of athletes and athletics-related injuries. She has now worked with student-athletes from, amongst others, Atlanta International School, Blessed Trinity, Galloway, Lovett, Marist, Pace, West Minister, and Woodward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Mcgrane</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</guid>
      <description>Michael McGrane served four years active duty in The U.S. Army. During his service, he trained at The Academy of Health Science, FT Sam Huston, Texas and was assigned to medical company Martin Army Hospital, FT Benning, GA.
Upon returning to civilian life, Michael was employed at The Hughston Orthopaedic and Sports Medicine Clinic and remained there for over twelve years.
In the early nineties, he left Columbus and began working the commercial side of radiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molly Myers</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/molly-myers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/molly-myers/</guid>
      <description>Molly Myers graduated from Virginia Tech in 1995 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Chemistry.
After graduation she began her career in medical research at Johns Hopkins School of Medicine in Baltimore, Maryland studying nuclear envelope formation. Upon moving to Boston, Massachusetts in 1996 she continued her career at the Dana Farber Cancer Institute where she worked in the field of breast cancer research. Leaving academic research in 2000 she joined the Molecular and Cellular Oncology group at Millennium Pharmaceuticals with a focus on prostate cancer research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regilyn W. Fish, Practice Manager</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/regilyn-fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/regilyn-fish/</guid>
      <description>Regilyn graduated from The University of Alabama in 2002 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Athletic Training and a minor in Nutrition.
While working towards her degree, she covered several Division I sports including football, men’s tennis, softball and women’s basketball.
She obtained her NATABOC certification for athletic training in 2002. She began her career as the head athletic trainer for Briarwood Christian High School in Birmingham, Alabama while working for Healthsouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiffany Jackson</title>
      <link>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/tiffany-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantcooksey.github.io/MyersSportsMedicine/staff-bios/tiffany-jackson/</guid>
      <description>Born and raised in Atlanta, Tiffany Jackson attended Southside High School and went on to obtain an Associates degree in Health Information Technology. Tiffany loves helping others and spending time with family and friends. She has one daughter and is currently a senior at Mercer University slated to graduate in May 2015 with a degree in liberal arts. Her plans are to obtain a Masters in School Counseling from Mercer as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>