<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:44:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DonJoy UltraSling Quadrant</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/shoulder-sling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:44:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/shoulder-sling/</guid>
      <description>The Donjoy Ultrasling Quadrant is a state of the art shoulder brace designed to stabilize the upper limb after shoulder surgery. The brace was designed by Dr. Myers for the comfort and rehabilitation of his patients. This is one of the many innovations that Dr. Myers has contributed to the field of orthopaedic surgery. 3 years in development, the Ultrasling Quadrant has many advantages over the prior shoulder immobilizers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACL Animation</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/acl-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:43:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/acl-animation/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenna Williams, MS, LAT, ATC, OTC</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/jenna-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 23:28:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/jenna-williams/</guid>
      <description>Jenna graduated in 2010 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Athletic Training with a minor in Health Science, from Marietta College in Marietta, Ohio. While attending Marietta College, she also played for their Division III soccer team. While working towards her degree, she covered several Division III sports including football, track and field, soccer, softball and women’s basketball. Jenna obtained her NATABOC certification and state licensure for athletic training in 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ross Brakeville PT, DPT, STC, TPI-L3</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ross-brakeville/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 23:23:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ross-brakeville/</guid>
      <description>Ross Brakeville, DPT, is the owner of Georgia Sports Medicine Specialists, LLC, and is a recognized expert in sports medicine and orthopedics. Dr. Brakeville received his undergraduate degrees in science and physical therapy from Maryville University, St. Louis, going on to earn his Doctor of physical therapy with a specialty in sports physical therapy from the University of St. Augustine in Florida. While he has a passion for and expertise in Golf, he is a certified level 3 Golf Medical Professional and published two books on golf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQs about Makoplasty</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/faqs-about-makoplasty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:02:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/faqs-about-makoplasty/</guid>
      <description>What is MAKOplasty&amp;reg;? MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Partial Knee Resurfacing is an innovative treatment option for adults living with early to midstage OA in the medial (inner), patellofemoral (top), or lateral (outer) compartments of the knee. It is powered by the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System, which allows for consistently reproducible precision in performing partial knee resurfacing.
During the procedure, the diseased portion of the knee is resurfaced, sparing the patient’s healthy bone and surrounding tissue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makoplasty Partial Knee Resurfacing</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 12:48:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing/</guid>
      <description>Partial knee replacement is a treatment option for people with early to mid-stage osteoarthritis (OA) that has not yet impacted their entire knee. Only the diseased portion of the knee is replaced, sparing healthy bone and the ligaments known as the ACL (anterior cruciate ligament) and PCL (posterior cruciate ligament).
MAKOplasty Partial Knee Resurfacing is an advanced partial knee surgery performed with the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System. It can be performed as a unicompartmental procedure to address OA in any of the three compartments of the knee: the medial (inner), patellofemoral (top), or lateral (outer) compartments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makoplasty Total Hip Replacement</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-total-hip-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 12:44:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-total-hip-replacement/</guid>
      <description>MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Total Hip Replacement is powered by the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System. It is indicated for adults who suffer from non-inflammatory or inflammatory degenerative joint disease. The RIO&amp;reg; robotic arm advanced technology allows surgeons to achieve a new level of accuracy.
Who is a Candidate for MAKOplasty&amp;reg;? If your symptoms aren’t responding to non-surgical solutions, or your pain can no longer be controlled by medication, you may be a candidate for MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Total Hip Replacement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System Rio</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/robotic-arm-interactive-orthopedic-system-rio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 12:37:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/robotic-arm-interactive-orthopedic-system-rio/</guid>
      <description>The RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System features three dimensional pre-surgical planning. During surgery, the RIO&amp;reg; provides the surgeon with real-time visual, tactile and auditory feedback to facilitate optimal joint resurfacing and implant positioning. It is this optimal placement that can result in more natural knee motion following surgery.
RIO&amp;reg; Features: Accurately plan implant size, orientation and alignment utilizing CT-derived 3-D modeling Enabling the pre-resection capture of patient-specific kinematic tracking through full flexion and extension Real-time intra-operative adjustments for correct knee kinematics and soft-tissue balance Minimally invasive and bone sparing, with minimal tissue trauma for faster recovery</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charles - ACL and Meniscus</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/charles-acl-and-meniscus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:01:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/charles-acl-and-meniscus/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leigh - Knee Surgeries</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/leigh-knee-surgeries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/leigh-knee-surgeries/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. Patch - Knee Surgeries</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/mrs-patch-knee-surgeries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:58:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/mrs-patch-knee-surgeries/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryan - Wrist Surgery</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/ryan-wrist-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:56:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/ryan-wrist-surgery/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ricky – Knee Surgery</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/rickyknee-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:50:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/rickyknee-surgery/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knee Surgery</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/knee-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:49:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/knee-surgery/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kirk - Shoulder and Knee Surgery</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/kirkshoulder-and-knee-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:47:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/kirkshoulder-and-knee-surgery/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paula - Partial Knee Replacement</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/paula-partial-knee-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:32:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/paula-partial-knee-replacement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adhesive Capsulitis</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:17:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</guid>
      <description>Adhesive capsulitis is when a person loses the ability to move their shoulder around in all directions without pain. This problem is commonly referred to as a frozen shoulder, as the shoulder usually becomes stiff and will be hard to move at all. The causes of ashesive capsulitis are somewhat unknown and tend to happen randomly.
What are the Symptoms of Adhesive Capsulitis? A shoulder should be able to move in all directions without any stiffness or pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slap Tears</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:15:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</guid>
      <description>A SLAP tear, also known as a superior labral tear, is when part of the shoulder joint known as the labrum is torn. The shoulder is similar to the hip as they are both ball and socket joints, but the shoulder joint is very shallow, so it is unstable. The labrum helps make the shoulder more stable by forming a cup that the end of the humerus can move around in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labral Tears</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:11:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</guid>
      <description>The shoulder joint is similar to the hip as they are both ball and socket joints. The shoulder joint’s socket is very shallow though, which inherently makes the shoulder joint unstable. This means that extra support in the shoulder is needed as the shoulder bones aren’t held in place adequately.shoulder-labrum-tear
 The labrum is what compensates for the shallow socket the shoulder joint has. The labrum is a cuff of cartilage that forms a cup for the end of the arm bone (the humerus) to move around in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frozen Shoulder Symptoms</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:08:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>A frozen shoulder causes symptoms easily recognizable by a doctor. The most noticeable symptom is restricted movement in the shoulder. It is possible for other conditions to have similar symptoms as a frozen shoulder, such as a rotator cuff tear, so always have your medical problem diagnosed properly by a doctor. There are different causes of frozen shoulders.
Common Frozen Shoulder Symptoms:  Limited and restricted movement of the shoulder Shoulder pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Frozen Shoulder?</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:06:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</guid>
      <description>A frozen shoulder, also known as adhesive capsulitis, is when motion of the shoulder joint is restricted. The cause of frozen shoulders isn’t well understood, and it usually happens randomly for no known reason. A frozen will cause the capsule around the shoulder joint to contract, which forms scar tissue.
Causes of a Frozen Shoulder Generally, a frozen shoulder will occur without an associated injury or cause. It’s possible for a patient to develop a frozen shoulder after some sort of injury, but that is usually not the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of a Dislocated Shoulder</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:04:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</guid>
      <description>Shoulder dislocation is a common injury that usually results from a wide variety of sports. Generally when a shoulder is dislocated, the head of the humerus (the upper arm bone) is forced forwards when the arm is turned outwards and being held out to the side. This dislocation, known as an anterior dislocation, makes up approximately 95% of all shoulder dislocations.
 The other 5% of dislocations, posterior dislocations, inferior dislocations, superior dislocations, or intra thoracic dislocations, are rarer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of a Rotator Cuff Tear</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</guid>
      <description>The rotator cuff is a group of muscles which work together and are responsible for the shoulder (Glenohumeral) joint’s stability while it moves and rotates. The rotator cuff muscles include Supraspinatus, Infraspinatus, Teres Minor, and the Subscapularis.
The Supraspinatus and Infraspinatus are the most commonly injured rotator cuff muscles. These injuries are usually related to sports involved with a lot of shoulder rotation, such as swimming, pitching a baseball, or bowling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of an ACL Tear</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:52:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</guid>
      <description>The anterior cruciate ligament, also known as the ACL, is one of the major cruciate ligaments that are located within the joints of the knee. The ACL provides stability to your knees, along with preventing over-bending and over-straightening of the knee. The ligament is connected between the tibia and femur. A torn ACL can refer to any injury caused to the ligament. A number of different things can cause a town ACL, such as a twisting force applied to the knee while the foot is firmly placed on the ground, or a direct blow to the knee upon a landing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meniscus Tears</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:47:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</guid>
      <description>The meniscus is a small, “c” shaped piece of cartilage that acts as a cushion for the knee joint. They sit between the shin bone (tibia) and the thigh bone (femur), with one being on the outside and one being on the inside of the knee.
What Is a Meniscus Tear? A meniscus tear usually occurs during movements that forcefully rotate the knee while the knee is bearing weight, which results in the piece of cartilage being torn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articular Cartilage Tear Information</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:44:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</guid>
      <description>What is articular cartilage? Articular cartilage, also known as hyaline cartilage, is a very smooth yet hard material made up of the protein collagen. The cartilage is located on a bone’s articulating surfaces (surfaces of a bone that come in contact with other bones). It allows for the smooth interaction between two bones in a joint.
How does articular cartilage get injured? Damage can result in the articular cartilage as an isolated incident or occur due to another knee injury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five Most Common Sports Injuries</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/sports-medicine/five-common-sports-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:29:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/sports-medicine/five-common-sports-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Many people play sports in some way or another, whether they are playing for fun in their backyard or competitively on a team. Exercising by playing sports can be very beneficial to your health, but sometimes these benefits to your health are outweighed by negative things, such as an injury. The severity of these injuries can range from minor to very serious, with some injuries requiring surgery to fully heal. These injuries may be caused from poor training practices, improper equipment, flawed techniques, or may just be an accident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cigna</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/cigna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:16:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/cigna/</guid>
      <description>CIGNA is a global health service company, dedicated to helping people improve their health, well-being and security. We provide an integrated suite of health, life, accident, disability and other wellness benefits to groups and individuals, serving over 45 million people throughout the United States and around the world.
Dr. Myers accepts CIGNA as a form of health insurance.
Cigna Homepage
Information taken from cigna.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United Health Care</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/united-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 23:57:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/united-health-care/</guid>
      <description>UnitedHealthcare is an operating division of UnitedHealth Group, the largest single health carrier in the United States.
As a recognized leader in the health and well-being industry, United Health Care strives to:
 Improve the quality and effectiveness of health care for all Americans Enhance access to health benefits Create products and services that make health care more affordable Use technology to make the health care system easier to navigate  Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aetna</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/aetna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:17:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/aetna/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Myers accepts Aetna as a form of health insurance.
Aetna offers “offer a broad range of traditional and consumer-directed health insurance products and related services. These include medical, pharmacy, dental, behavioral health, group life, long-term care and disability plans and medical management capabilities. Our customers include employer groups, individuals, college students, part-time and hourly workers, health plans and government-sponsored plans.”
Dr. Myers accepts Aetna as a form of health insurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Cross Blue Shield</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/blue-cross-blue-shield/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:08:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/blue-cross-blue-shield/</guid>
      <description>One of the most trusted names in health coverage, Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Georgia has been providing quality health benefits to state residents for over 70 years.
Dr. Myers accepts Blue Cross Blue Shield as a form of health insurance.
Blue Cross Blue Shield Homepage
Blue Cross Blue Shield Georgia Homepage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/about/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/about/contact-us/</guid>
      <description>  Hours Our office hours are as listed:
Monday 8AM–12PM, 1:30PM–5PM Tuesday 8AM–12PM, 1:30PM–5PM Wednesday 8AM–12PM, 1:30PM–5PM Thursday 8AM–12PM, 1:30PM–5PM Friday 8AM–12PM, 1:30PM–5PM   Contact Call Us: (404) 352-8156
Fax Us: (404) 350-9405
Location 3200 Downwood Cir NW #340
Atlanta, GA 30327

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Myers Key Information</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/dr-myers/key-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/dr-myers/key-information/</guid>
      <description>Specialties Open &amp;amp; Arthroscopic Cartilage Replacement Procedures Knee and Shoulder Arthroscopy Sports Injuries – ACL Reconstruction
 Board Certification American Board of Orthopaedic Surgery
ABOS Subspecialty Certification in Sports Medicine
 Hospital Affiliations St. Joseph’s Hospital Atlanta Outpatient Surgery Center Piedmont West Outpatient Surgery Center
 Fellowships Sports Medicine American Sports Medicine Institute Birmingham, Alabama
Orthopaedic Trauma Harvard School of Medicine Boston, MA
 Postgraduate Training Orthopaedic Residency Harvard School of Medicine Boston, MA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kristiann Settles</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/kristiann-settles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/kristiann-settles/</guid>
      <description>Kristiann Settles obtained her Bachelor of Science in Exercise &amp;amp; Health Science from Kennesaw State University in 2014. Early in her studies, Kristiann conducted an analysis in Biomechanics, which stimulated an interest in orthopaedic rehabilitation and encouraged her to assist in rehabilitating a variety of athletes and athletics-related injuries. She has now worked with student-athletes from, amongst others, Atlanta International School, Blessed Trinity, Galloway, Lovett, Marist, Pace, West Minister, and Woodward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Mcgrane</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</guid>
      <description>Michael McGrane served four years active duty in The U.S. Army. During his service, he trained at The Academy of Health Science, FT Sam Huston, Texas and was assigned to medical company Martin Army Hospital, FT Benning, GA.
Upon returning to civilian life, Michael was employed at The Hughston Orthopaedic and Sports Medicine Clinic and remained there for over twelve years.
In the early nineties, he left Columbus and began working the commercial side of radiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molly Myers</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/molly-myers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/molly-myers/</guid>
      <description>Molly Myers graduated from Virginia Tech in 1995 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Chemistry.
After graduation she began her career in medical research at Johns Hopkins School of Medicine in Baltimore, Maryland studying nuclear envelope formation. Upon moving to Boston, Massachusetts in 1996 she continued her career at the Dana Farber Cancer Institute where she worked in the field of breast cancer research. Leaving academic research in 2000 she joined the Molecular and Cellular Oncology group at Millennium Pharmaceuticals with a focus on prostate cancer research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patient Concierge Service</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/patient-info/concierge-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/patient-info/concierge-service/</guid>
      <description>Benefits No wait time. After patient check in and verification of insurance the patient is immediately placed in the doctor’s examination room and evaluated as soon as possible.
Pre-appointment Paperwork. Option to complete medical history questionnaire and intake forms online prior to appointment.
Private area for in-office paperwork. Sound proof area isolated from regular waiting room available for the patient to complete online medical history and sign patient intake forms (if not completed online).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regilyn W. Fish, Practice Manager</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/regilyn-fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/regilyn-fish/</guid>
      <description>Regilyn graduated from The University of Alabama in 2002 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Athletic Training and a minor in Nutrition.
While working towards her degree, she covered several Division I sports including football, men’s tennis, softball and women’s basketball.
She obtained her NATABOC certification for athletic training in 2002. She began her career as the head athletic trainer for Briarwood Christian High School in Birmingham, Alabama while working for Healthsouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiffany Jackson</title>
      <link>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/tiffany-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/tiffany-jackson/</guid>
      <description>Born and raised in Atlanta, Tiffany obtained a Bachelors Degree at Mercer University in Liberal Arts and Communication, Tiffany loves helping others plans to obtain her Masters in school counseling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>