<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:55:26 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cash Pay FAQs</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/cash-pay-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:55:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/cash-pay-faq/</guid>
      <description>Why has Dr. Myers transitioned to a cash-pay model? Dr. Myers has made the decision to shift to a cash-pay model to protect and restore the integrity of the physician-patient relationship. Over the years, insurance companies have increasingly interfered with medical decisions by limiting treatment options, delaying necessary care, and denying coverage for essential procedures.

Dr. Myers believes that patient care should be dictated by the needs and well-being of the patient, not by the policies of insurance companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cash Pay Pricing</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/self-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 09:55:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/self-pay/</guid>
      <description>At Myers Sports Medicine and Orthopaedic Center, we recognize that navigating healthcare costs can be challenging. To make your care more accessible and straightforward, we proudly offer transparent self-pay pricing for our services. Self-pay rates are available exclusively for payments made in full at the time of service.

Please note: commercial and government-sponsored insurance plans do not qualify for self-pay pricing and cannot be submitted for reimbursement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryan Klosterman</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ryan-ingraffia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 08:07:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ryan-ingraffia/</guid>
      <description>Ryan graduated from Kennesaw State University in 2013 with a bachelor’s degree in Exercise and Health Science with an interest in Physical Therapy. She then went on to Lanier Technical College to complete the PT Assistant program and graduated in May 2016. Ryan has orthopedic experience specializing interest in sports medicine, aquatic therapy, and balance retraining. Ryan is now PT Assistant to Dr. Ross Brakeville.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DonJoy UltraSling Quadrant</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/shoulder-sling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:44:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/shoulder-sling/</guid>
      <description>The Donjoy Ultrasling Quadrant is a state of the art shoulder brace designed to stabilize the upper limb after shoulder surgery. The brace was designed by Dr. Myers for the comfort and rehabilitation of his patients. This is one of the many innovations that Dr. Myers has contributed to the field of orthopaedic surgery. 3 years in development, the Ultrasling Quadrant has many advantages over the prior shoulder immobilizers.
    Patient comfort - The Ultrasling Quadrant stabilizes the arm by supporting its weight on the hip as well as suspending it from the opposite shoulder with a strap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACL Animation</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/acl-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:43:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/acl-animation/</guid>
      <description>The video below demonstrates the N8TIVE ACL reconstruction surgical process in the knee.

  A tissue graft is removed from the patient, typically a tendon from the hamstring. The graft is prepared with sutures and resized according to the size of the patient&amp;rsquo;s original ACL.
A pin is placed on the Anteromedial (AM) Bundle footprint on the femur, the site where the ACL used to be attached. This pin is used as a guide to drill two tunnels for the ACL graft, one anteromedial (AM) and one posterolateral (PL).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenna Hagan, MS, LAT, ATC, OTC, Practice Manager</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/jenna-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 23:28:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/jenna-williams/</guid>
      <description>Jenna is from Columbus, Ohio and graduated in 2010 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Athletic Training with a minor in Health Science, from Marietta College in Marietta, Ohio. While attending Marietta College, she also played for their Division III soccer team. As she was working towards her degree, she covered several Division III sports including football, track and field, soccer, softball and women’s basketball. Jenna obtained her NATABOC certification and state licensure for athletic training in 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQs about Makoplasty</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/faqs-about-makoplasty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:02:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/faqs-about-makoplasty/</guid>
      <description>What is MAKOplasty&amp;reg;?  MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Partial Knee Resurfacing is an innovative treatment option for adults living with early to midstage OA in the medial (inner), patellofemoral (top), or lateral (outer) compartments of the knee. It is powered by the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System, which allows for consistently reproducible precision in performing partial knee resurfacing.
During the procedure, the diseased portion of the knee is resurfaced, sparing the patient’s healthy bone and surrounding tissue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makoplasty Partial Knee Resurfacing</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 12:48:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing/</guid>
      <description>Partial knee replacement is a treatment option for people with early to mid-stage osteoarthritis (OA) that has not yet impacted their entire knee. Only the diseased portion of the knee is replaced, sparing healthy bone and the ligaments known as the ACL (anterior cruciate ligament) and PCL (posterior cruciate ligament).
Partial knee replacement resurfaces only the damaged compartment of the knee while preserving the remaining healthy anatomy
  MAKOplasty Partial Knee Resurfacing is an advanced partial knee surgery performed with the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makoplasty Total Hip Replacement</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-total-hip-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 12:44:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-total-hip-replacement/</guid>
      <description>MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Total Hip Replacement is powered by the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System. It is indicated for adults who suffer from non-inflammatory or inflammatory degenerative joint disease. The RIO&amp;reg; robotic arm advanced technology allows surgeons to achieve a new level of accuracy.

Who is a Candidate for MAKOplasty&amp;reg;?  If your symptoms aren’t responding to non-surgical solutions, or your pain can no longer be controlled by medication, you may be a candidate for MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Total Hip Replacement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic (RIO) System</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/robotic-arm-interactive-orthopedic-system-rio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 12:37:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/robotic-arm-interactive-orthopedic-system-rio/</guid>
      <description>The RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System features three dimensional pre-surgical planning. During surgery, the RIO&amp;reg; provides the surgeon with real-time visual, tactile and auditory feedback to facilitate optimal joint resurfacing and implant positioning. It is this optimal placement that can result in more natural knee motion following surgery.

RIO&amp;reg; Features:  Accurately plan implant size, orientation and alignment utilizing CT-derived 3-D modeling Enabling the pre-resection capture of patient-specific kinematic tracking through full flexion and extension Real-time intra-operative adjustments for correct knee kinematics and soft-tissue balance Minimally invasive and bone sparing, with minimal tissue trauma for faster recovery</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charles - ACL and Meniscus</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/charles-acl-and-meniscus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:01:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/charles-acl-and-meniscus/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leigh - Knee Surgeries</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/leigh-knee-surgeries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/leigh-knee-surgeries/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. Patch - Knee Surgeries</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/mrs-patch-knee-surgeries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:58:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/mrs-patch-knee-surgeries/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryan - Wrist Surgery</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/ryan-wrist-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:56:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/ryan-wrist-surgery/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ricky – Knee Surgery</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/rickyknee-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:50:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/rickyknee-surgery/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knee Surgery</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/knee-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:49:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/knee-surgery/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kirk - Shoulder and Knee Surgery</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/kirkshoulder-and-knee-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:47:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/kirkshoulder-and-knee-surgery/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paula - Partial Knee Replacement</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/paula-partial-knee-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:32:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/testimonials/paula-partial-knee-replacement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adhesive Capsulitis</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:17:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</guid>
      <description>Adhesive capsulitis of the shoulder is characterized by a reduction in shoulder range of motion and pain with movement. This condition is commonly referred to as frozen shoulder, as the shoulder usually becomes &amp;ldquo;frozen&amp;rdquo; in place and may become difficult to move at all. The causes of adhesive capsulitis are somewhat unknown and the condition tends to develop without a specfic mechanism of injury.

What are the Symptoms of Adhesive Capsulitis?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slap Tears</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:15:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</guid>
      <description>A SLAP tear, also known as a superior labral tear, occurs when part of the shoulder joint known as the labrum is torn. The shoulder is similar to the hip in that they are both ball and socket joints, but the shoulder joint is considerably more shallow and less stable as a result. The labrum helps overcome this instability by forming a &amp;ldquo;cup&amp;rdquo; that surrounds the head of the humerus and provides additional support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labral Tears</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:11:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</guid>
      <description>The shoulder joint is similar to the hip as they are both ball and socket joints. However, the shoulder joint’s socket is more shallow, which makes it inherently less stable. This means that extra support is needed to adequately hold the shoulder bones in place.

 
To compensate for this shallow socket, the shoulder has a cuff of cartilage known as the labrum surrounding its joint. The labrum forms a cup for the end of the arm bone (the humerus) to move around in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Frozen Shoulder?</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:06:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</guid>
      <description>Frozen shoulder, also known as adhesive capsulitis, is characterized by pain and restriction of motion in the shoulder joint. Normally, the shoulder allows a greater range of motion than any other joint in the body. However, in patients with a frozen shoulder, the capsule around the shoulder joint contracts, forming bands of scar tissue (adhesions). These adhesions &#34;freeze&#34; the head of the humerus (upper arm bone) in place, causing pain and restricting movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of a Dislocated Shoulder</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:04:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</guid>
      <description>Shoulder dislocation is a relatively common injury in a wide variety of sports. Generally, when a shoulder is dislocated, the head of the humerus (the upper arm bone) is forced forwards when the arm is turned outwards and being held out to the side. This dislocation, known as an anterior dislocation, makes up approximately 95% of all shoulder dislocations.
 Posterior are the second most common type of dislocation with 3% or dislocations being posterior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of a Rotator Cuff Tear</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</guid>
      <description>The rotator cuff is a group of muscles and tendons that are responsible for the glenohumeral (shoulder) joint’s stability while it moves and rotates. The rotator cuff includes the Supraspinatus, Infraspinatus, Teres Minor, and the Subscapularis muscles as well as their associated tendons. Of these, the supraspinatus and infraspinatus tendons are the most commonly injured. When healthy, these tissues surround the shoulder joint and keep the head of the humerus (upper arm bone) in place during movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of an ACL Tear</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:52:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</guid>
      <description>The anterior cruciate ligament, also known as the ACL, is one of the major ligaments within the knee joint. The ligament connects the femur and tibia bones, providing stability to the knee and preventing over-bending and over-straightening. An ACL tear can refer to any injury caused to the ligament, from a minor sprain to a true tear.  
ACL tears are one of the most common types of sports injuries, and are typically caused by motions that apply twisting forces on the knee such as pivoting one one foot or stopping suddenly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meniscus Tears</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:47:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</guid>
      <description>The menisci are small, “C”-shaped pieces of cartilage that act as cushions for the knee joint. Each knee has both a medial (inner, towards the midline of the body) and lateral (outer) meniscus, both sitting on top of the tibia (shin bone). How does a Meniscus Become Torn?  A meniscus tear usually occurs during movements that forcefully rotate the knee while the knee is bearing weight, which results in the piece of cartilage being torn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articular Cartilage Tear Information</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:44:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</guid>
      <description>What is articular cartilage?  Articular cartilage, also known as hyaline cartilage, is a very smooth yet hard material made up of the protein collagen. The cartilage is located on a bone’s articulating surfaces (surfaces of a bone that come in contact with other bones). It allows for the smooth interaction between two bones in joints such as the knee.
 
How does articular cartilage get injured?  Damage to the articular cartilage may occur as an isolated incident or may develop due to another knee injury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five Most Common Sports Injuries</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/sports-medicine/five-common-sports-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:29:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/sports-medicine/five-common-sports-injuries/</guid>
      <description>While playing sports can be very beneficial to your health, all sports carry some risk of injury. The severity of these injuries can range from minor to very serious, with some more severe injuries requiring surgery to fully correct. Injury can result from poor training practices, improper equipment, flawed techniques, or simply by accident. Improper conditioning, such as insufficent warm-up or stretching of muscles before exercise, may also cause injury. Five of the most common sports-related injuries are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cigna</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/cigna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:16:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/cigna/</guid>
      <description>CIGNA is a global health service company, dedicated to helping people improve their health, well-being and security. We provide an integrated suite of health, life, accident, disability and other wellness benefits to groups and individuals, serving over 45 million people throughout the United States and around the world.
Dr. Myers accepts CIGNA as a form of health insurance.
Cigna Homepage
Information taken from cigna.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United Health Care</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/united-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 23:57:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/united-health-care/</guid>
      <description>UnitedHealthcare is an operating division of UnitedHealth Group, the largest single health carrier in the United States.
As a recognized leader in the health and well-being industry, United Health Care strives to:
 Improve the quality and effectiveness of health care for all Americans Enhance access to health benefits Create products and services that make health care more affordable Use technology to make the health care system easier to navigate  Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aetna</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/aetna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:17:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/aetna/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Myers accepts Aetna as a form of health insurance.
Aetna offers “offer a broad range of traditional and consumer-directed health insurance products and related services. These include medical, pharmacy, dental, behavioral health, group life, long-term care and disability plans and medical management capabilities. Our customers include employer groups, individuals, college students, part-time and hourly workers, health plans and government-sponsored plans.”
Dr. Myers accepts Aetna as a form of health insurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Cross Blue Shield</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/blue-cross-blue-shield/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:08:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/blue-cross-blue-shield/</guid>
      <description>One of the most trusted names in health coverage, Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Georgia has been providing quality health benefits to state residents for over 70 years.
Dr. Myers accepts Blue Cross Blue Shield as a form of health insurance.
Blue Cross Blue Shield Homepage
Blue Cross Blue Shield Georgia Homepage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amy Prall, MS, LAT, ATC</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/amy-prall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/amy-prall/</guid>
      <description>Amy Prall is the Practice Manager for Myers Sports Medicine Orthopaedic Center.
Amy grew up in Cary, North Carolina before moving to Cleveland, TN to attend Lee University. She graduated in 2012 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Athletic Training. She also obtained her NATABOC certification and state licensure for athletic training in the same year.
In 2014, Amy went on to earn her Master of Science degree in Sports Medicine from Georgia State University in Atlanta, Georgia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Maggard, BS, EMT</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ben-maggard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ben-maggard/</guid>
      <description>Ben graduated from Auburn University Honors Program in 2023, earning his B.S. in Biomedical Sciences.
In addition to his work at our clinic since graduation, he works part-time as an EMT for Metro Atlanta Ambulance Services and as an EMT instructor.
His areas of interest include volunteering to address food insecurity around Atlanta, building computers, and golfing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bre-anne Naughton, MHA</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/breanne-naughton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/breanne-naughton/</guid>
      <description>Bre-anne Naughton is the Front Office Specialist handling all Physical Therapy matters.
In late 2021, Bre-anne moved to Georgia from Virginia. She graduated in 2018 with a bachelor’s degree in Health Services Management from Norfolk State University and with her master’s degree in Healthcare Administration from George Mason University in 2021. She brings seven years of medical office and four years of medical billing experience to the practice. She believes that healthcare should be pleasant for all stakeholders and is determined to provide exceptional service to her community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caroline Rodgers, PA-C</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/caroline-rodgers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/caroline-rodgers/</guid>
      <description>Caroline Rodgers is a Physical Assistant (PA-C) treating patients in our office Monday-Friday.
Caroline is from Woodstock, GA. She earned her undergraduate degree from the University of Georgia where she competed all four years on the Varsity Women’s Soccer Team. After her time at UGA, Caroline completed her medical training at Mercer University’s Physician Assistant Program.
Caroline’s medical interests include knee and shoulder injuries and regenerative medicine. Caroline lives in Marietta with her husband and two goldendoodles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/about/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/about/contact-us/</guid>
      <description>   Hours  Our office hours are as listed: Monday 8AM–12PM, 1:30PM–5PM Tuesday 8AM–12PM, 1:30PM–5PM Wednesday 8AM–12PM, 1:30PM–5PM Thursday 8AM–12PM, 1:30PM–5PM Friday - Sunday, CLOSED     Contact  Call Us: (404) 352-8156 Fax Us: (404) 350-9405    Location  5667 Peachtree Dunwoody Rd #220, Atlanta, GA 30342    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Myers Key Information</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/dr-myers/key-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/dr-myers/key-information/</guid>
      <description>Specialties  Open &amp;amp; Arthroscopic Cartilage Replacement Procedures Knee and Shoulder Arthroscopy Sports Injuries – ACL Reconstruction

Board Certification  American Board of Orthopaedic Surgery
ABOS Subspecialty Certification in Sports Medicine

Hospital Affiliations  St. Joseph’s Hospital Atlanta Outpatient Surgery Center Piedmont West Outpatient Surgery Center

Fellowships  Sports Medicine American Sports Medicine Institute Birmingham, Alabama
Orthopaedic Trauma Harvard School of Medicine Boston, MA

Postgraduate Training  Orthopaedic Residency Harvard School of Medicine Boston, MA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Mcgrane</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</guid>
      <description>Michael McGrane served four years active duty in The U.S. Army. During his service, he trained at The Academy of Health Science, FT Sam Huston, Texas and was assigned to medical company Martin Army Hospital, FT Benning, GA.
Upon returning to civilian life, Michael was employed at The Hughston Orthopaedic and Sports Medicine Clinic and remained there for over twelve years.
In the early nineties, he left Columbus and began working the commercial side of radiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molly Myers</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/molly-myers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/molly-myers/</guid>
      <description>Molly Myers graduated from Virginia Tech in 1995 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Chemistry.
After graduation she began her career in medical research at Johns Hopkins School of Medicine in Baltimore, Maryland studying nuclear envelope formation. Upon moving to Boston, Massachusetts in 1996 she continued her career at the Dana Farber Cancer Institute where she worked in the field of breast cancer research. Leaving academic research in 2000 she joined the Molecular and Cellular Oncology group at Millennium Pharmaceuticals with a focus on prostate cancer research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patient Concierge Service</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/patient-info/concierge-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/patient-info/concierge-service/</guid>
      <description>Benefits  No wait time. After patient check in, the patient is immediately placed in the doctor’s examination room and evaluated as soon as possible.
Pre-appointment Paperwork. Option to complete medical history questionnaire and intake forms online prior to appointment.
Private area for in-office paperwork. Sound proof area isolated from regular waiting room available for the patient to complete online medical history and sign patient intake forms (if not completed online).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stacy Lee</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/stacy-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/stacy-lee/</guid>
      <description>Stacy relocated from Oregon where she gained extensive experience working as a medical office coordinator for over 10 years. She has received many outstanding patient service awards over the years and enjoys building close relationships with her patients. She and her husband currently live in Acworth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>