<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Staff Bios on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Staff Bios on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 08:07:04 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryan Ingraffia</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ryan-ingraffia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 08:07:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ryan-ingraffia/</guid>
      <description>Ryan graduated from Kennesaw State University in 2013 with a bachelor’s degree in Exercise and Health Science with an interest in Physical Therapy. She then went on to Lanier Technical College to complete the PT Assistant program and graduated in May 2016. Ryan has orthopedic experience specializing interest in sports medicine, aquatic therapy, and balance retraining. Ryan is now PT Assistant to Dr. Ross Brakeville.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenna Williams, MS, LAT, ATC, OTC, Practice Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/jenna-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 23:28:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/jenna-williams/</guid>
      <description>Jenna graduated in 2010 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Athletic Training with a minor in Health Science, from Marietta College in Marietta, Ohio. While attending Marietta College, she also played for their Division III soccer team. While working towards her degree, she covered several Division III sports including football, track and field, soccer, softball and women’s basketball. Jenna obtained her NATABOC certification and state licensure for athletic training in 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ross Brakeville PT, DPT, STC, TPI-CFI</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ross-brakeville/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 23:23:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ross-brakeville/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ross Brakeville, PT, DPT, STC, TPI-CFI is the owner of Georgia Sports Medicine Specialists. Dr. Brakeville graduated from Maryville College in 1987 with degrees in Science and Physical Therapy. He went on to earn a Doctor of Physical Therapy and Specialty Certification in Sports Physical Therapy from the University of St. Augustine in 2007. Dr. Brakeville has continued his pursuit of orthopaedic and sports medicine education with clinical internships in pediatric and adult orthopedic programs facilitated by recognized physicians in Athens, Macon and Atlanta Georgia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kristiann Settles</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/kristiann-settles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/kristiann-settles/</guid>
      <description>Kristiann Settles obtained her Bachelor of Science in Exercise &amp;amp; Health Science from Kennesaw State University in 2014. Early in her studies, Kristiann conducted an analysis in Biomechanics, which stimulated an interest in orthopaedic rehabilitation and encouraged her to assist in rehabilitating a variety of athletes and athletics-related injuries. She has now worked with student-athletes from, amongst others, Atlanta International School, Blessed Trinity, Galloway, Lovett, Marist, Pace, West Minister, and Woodward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Mcgrane</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</guid>
      <description>Michael McGrane served four years active duty in The U.S. Army. During his service, he trained at The Academy of Health Science, FT Sam Huston, Texas and was assigned to medical company Martin Army Hospital, FT Benning, GA.
Upon returning to civilian life, Michael was employed at The Hughston Orthopaedic and Sports Medicine Clinic and remained there for over twelve years.
In the early nineties, he left Columbus and began working the commercial side of radiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molly Myers</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/molly-myers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/molly-myers/</guid>
      <description>Molly Myers graduated from Virginia Tech in 1995 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Chemistry.
After graduation she began her career in medical research at Johns Hopkins School of Medicine in Baltimore, Maryland studying nuclear envelope formation. Upon moving to Boston, Massachusetts in 1996 she continued her career at the Dana Farber Cancer Institute where she worked in the field of breast cancer research. Leaving academic research in 2000 she joined the Molecular and Cellular Oncology group at Millennium Pharmaceuticals with a focus on prostate cancer research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiffany Jackson</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/tiffany-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/tiffany-jackson/</guid>
      <description>Born and raised in Atlanta, Tiffany obtained a Bachelors Degree at Mercer University in Liberal Arts and Communication, Tiffany loves helping others plans to obtain her Masters in school counseling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>