<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Featured Procedures on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/</link><description>Recent content in Featured Procedures on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:44:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DonJoy UltraSling Quadrant</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/shoulder-sling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:44:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/shoulder-sling/</guid><description>&lt;div class="oswald grid-1-bottom-p grid-1-top-p"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Donjoy Ultrasling Quadrant is a state of the art shoulder brace designed to stabilize the upper limb after shoulder surgery. The brace was designed by Dr. Myers for the comfort and rehabilitation of his patients. This is one of the many innovations that Dr. Myers has contributed to the field of orthopaedic surgery. 3 years in development, the Ultrasling Quadrant has many advantages over the prior shoulder immobilizers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ACL Animation</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/acl-animation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:43:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/acl-animation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The video below demonstrates the N8TIVE ACL reconstruction surgical process in the knee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class="text-center grid-2-bottom videowrapper"&gt;
 &lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xda39K69zjs" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tissue graft is removed from the patient, typically a tendon from the hamstring. The graft is prepared with sutures and resized according to the size of the patient&amp;rsquo;s original ACL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pin is placed on the Anteromedial (AM) Bundle footprint on the femur, the site where the ACL used to be attached. This pin is used as a guide to drill two tunnels for the ACL graft, one anteromedial (AM) and one posterolateral (PL). Two tunnels are used to more accurately mimic the anatomy of the native ACL, which has both an AM and PL bundle (illustrated at the end of the video). The tunnels are then resized to fit the ACL graft. A smaller drill is used to make a tunnel for the graft button.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>