<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Shoulder on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/</link><description>Recent content in The Shoulder on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:17:33 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adhesive Capsulitis</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:17:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Adhesive capsulitis of the shoulder is characterized by a reduction in shoulder range of motion and pain with movement. This condition is commonly referred to as &lt;a href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/"&gt;frozen shoulder&lt;/a&gt;, as the shoulder usually becomes &amp;ldquo;frozen&amp;rdquo; in place and may become difficult to move at all. The causes of adhesive capsulitis are somewhat unknown and the condition tends to develop without a specfic mechanism of injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-are-the-symptoms-of-adhesive-capsulitis"&gt;What are the Symptoms of Adhesive Capsulitis?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
A shoulder should be able to move in all directions without any stiffness or pain. However, when adhesiv capsulitis develops, the following movements may become more difficult or even painful:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raising your arms out to the sides of your body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reaching up towards the sky with both arms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reaching behind you, like trying to grab something out of the back seat of a car&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretending you are trying to unzip you’re the back of a dress or pull out your wallet from the back of your pants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reaching out straight in front of you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-are-the-causes-of-adhesive-capsulitis"&gt;What are the Causes of Adhesive Capsulitis?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Adhesive capsulitis often occurs during periods of inactivity due to other injuries, such as a torn rotator cuff, broken arm, or surgery recovery. The inflammation of the shoulder joint caused by such injuries may increase the chances of developing adhesive capsulitis if it goes untreated. This inflammation may cause the connective 
tissue in your shoulder joint to tighten, restricting movement of the joint and promoting the formation of adhesions. Age and demographic may also contribute to an increased risk of adhesive capsulitis, with adults over 40, especially women, more prone to this complication.</description></item><item><title>Slap Tears</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:15:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/slap-tears/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A SLAP tear, also known as a superior labral tear, occurs when part of the shoulder joint known as the labrum is torn. The shoulder is similar to the hip in that they are both ball and socket
joints, but the shoulder joint is considerably more shallow and less stable as a result. The labrum helps overcome this instability by forming a &amp;ldquo;cup&amp;rdquo; that surrounds the head of the humerus and provides additional support. As a result, when the labrum is torn the shoulder may become considerably less stable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Labral Tears</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:11:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/labral-tears/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The shoulder joint is similar to the hip as they are both ball and socket joints. However, the
shoulder joint’s socket is more shallow, which makes it inherently less stable. This means that extra support is needed to adequately hold the shoulder bones in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class="md-img-center text-center"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-sm" alt="Shoulder Labrum Tear" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/the-shoulder/shoulder-labrum-tear.gif"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compensate for this shallow socket, the shoulder has a cuff of cartilage known as the labrum surrounding its joint. The labrum forms a cup for the end of the arm bone (the humerus) to move
around in. The labrum circles the shallow shoulder socket (the glenoid) to make the socket
deeper. This cuff of cartilage allows the shoulder to have a wide range of movements, while at the same time improving stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What is a Frozen Shoulder?</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:06:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/</guid><description>&lt;div class = "row"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-md-5"&gt;
 &lt;div class="md-img-center text-center"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-sm" alt="Frozen Shoulder" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder-treatments.gif"&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div class = "col-md-7"&gt;
 Frozen shoulder, also known as 
 &lt;a href="../the-shoulder/adhesive-capsulitis/"&gt;adhesive capsulitis&lt;/a&gt;, is characterized by pain and restriction of motion in the shoulder joint. Normally, the shoulder allows a greater range of motion than 
 any other joint in the body. However, in patients with a frozen shoulder, the capsule around the shoulder joint contracts, forming bands of scar tissue (adhesions). These adhesions "freeze" the head of the humerus (upper arm bone) in place, causing pain and restricting movement. 
 The cause of frozen shoulder
 is not well understood, and the condition may develop even without a specfic mechanism of injury. 
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
## Common Symptoms of a Frozen Shoulder:
&lt;hr&gt;
* Limited and restricted movement of the shoulder
* Constant, dull aching shoulder pain that does not subside
* Trouble sleeping on the shoulder due to pain
* Difficulty doing simple tasks such as tying a shoe or brushing your hair
&lt;br&gt;
## Causes of a Frozen Shoulder
&lt;hr&gt;
Generally, frozen shoulders occur without an associated injury or cause. It is possible for a patient to develop a frozen shoulder after some sort of injury, but most occurences do not have a specific mechanism of injury.
&lt;p&gt;There are specific risk factors that may make a patient more likely to develop a a frozen shoulder, including:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Symptoms of a Dislocated Shoulder</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:04:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-dislocated-shoulder/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Shoulder dislocation is a relatively common injury in a wide variety of sports.
Generally, when a shoulder is dislocated, the head of the humerus (the upper arm bone) is
forced forwards when the arm is turned outwards and being held out to the side. This
dislocation, known as an anterior dislocation, makes up approximately 95% of all shoulder
dislocations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="md-img-center text-center"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-sm" alt="Dislocated Shoulder" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/the-shoulder/dislocated-shoulder.jpg"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
Posterior are the second most common type of dislocation with 3% or dislocations being 
posterior. The other 2% of dislocations include inferior dislocations, superior dislocations, and intra thoracic dislocations. Regardless of their classification, all dislocations can also cause a variety 
of complications and damage to surrounding structures such as muscles, tendons, or nerves. 
&lt;p&gt;The anatomy of the shoulder allows for a wide range of motion, but this also makes the joint more prone to dislocation. As a result, the shoulder is the most commonly dislocated joint, followed by elbow, knee, finger and wrist dislocations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Symptoms of a Rotator Cuff Tear</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 15:00:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/</guid><description>&lt;div class = "row"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-md-5"&gt;
 &lt;div class="md-img-center text-center"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-sm drop-shadow" alt="Rotator Cuff Tear" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/the-shoulder/rotator-cuff-tear.jpg"&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
 &lt;div class="col-md-7"&gt; 
 The rotator cuff is a group of muscles and tendons that are responsible for the 
 glenohumeral (shoulder) joint’s stability while it moves and rotates. 
 The rotator cuff includes the 
 Supraspinatus, Infraspinatus, Teres Minor, and the Subscapularis muscles as well as their associated tendons. Of these, the supraspinatus and infraspinatus tendons are the most commonly injured.
 When healthy, these tissues surround the shoulder joint and keep the head of the humerus (upper arm bone) in place during movement.
 As a result, injuries to the rotator cuff are usually related to sports that require excessive shoulder rotation, such 
 as swimming, baseball, or bowling.
 Problems with rotator cuff muscles are generally classified into two categories: 
 inflammation of structures in the joint, or tears of the tendons and muscles.
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="acute-rotator-cuff-tears"&gt;Acute Rotator Cuff Tears&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Acute tears of the rotator cuff usually result from a quick, sudden, and powerful movement such as following through on a baseball pitch or a sudden thrust with a canoe paddle.
&lt;h3 id="symptoms-of-an-acute-rotator-cuff-tear-may-include"&gt;Symptoms of an acute rotator cuff tear may include:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A sudden tearing/ripping sensation on the shoulder followed by severe pain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinpoint tenderness over the point of rupture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited movement due to pain or spasms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Severe pain for a few days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In severe cases, inability to raise arms outwards without help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="chronic-rotator-cuff-tears"&gt;Chronic Rotator Cuff Tears&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Chronic rotator cuff tears develop over an extended period of time and may be caused by repetitive motion or overuse. These tears usually occur at or near the tendon due to the tendon rubbing the overlying bone, causing fraying of the tendon and potentially a larger tear if untreated. Chronic tears tend to occur on the dominant side, and are more common in people aged 40 years or older. 
&lt;h3 id="symptoms-of-a-chronic-rotator-cuff-tear-may-include"&gt;Symptoms of a chronic rotator cuff tear may include:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pain is worse at night; may affect sleeping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pain becomes gradually stronger while arm becomes gradually weaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arm is eventually unable to be lifted outwards without help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>