<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mako on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/tags/mako/</link><description>Recent content in Mako on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 22:40:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/tags/mako/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MAKOplasty</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 22:40:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-makoplasty"&gt;What is MAKOplasty®?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MAKOplasty® Partial Knee Resurfacing and MAKOplasty® Total Hip Replacement are
enabled by the surgeon controlled RIO® robotic arm system, offering increased accuracy to
optimize surgical results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing"&gt;MAKOplasty® Partial Knee Resurfacing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://patients.stryker.com/knee-replacement/options/mako-robotic-arm-assisted-partial-knee"&gt;Partial Knee Replacement&lt;/a&gt; is a treatment option for adults living with early-to mid-stage
osteoarthritis (OA) that has not progressed to all three compartments of the knee.
MAKOplasty® Partial Knee Resurfacing is an advanced treatment option. It is powered
by the RIO® Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System, which allows the surgeon to
perform surgery accurately through a smaller incision as compared to manual procedures.
By selectively targeting the part of the knee damaged by OA, surgeons can resurface the
knee while sparing the healthy bone and ligaments surrounding it. Partial knee resurfacing may be done unicompartmentally (when only one area of the joint needs resurfacing) or bicompartmentally (when two areas of the joint need to be resurfaced). Both options maintain the surrounding healthy bone and ligaments, unlike total knee replacements.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>FAQs about Makoplasty</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/faqs-about-makoplasty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:02:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/faqs-about-makoplasty/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-makoplasty"&gt;What is MAKOplasty®?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
MAKOplasty&amp;reg; [Partial Knee Resurfacing](https://patients.stryker.com/knee-replacement/options/mako-robotic-arm-assisted-partial-knee) is an innovative treatment option for adults living with early to midstage OA in the medial (inner), patellofemoral (top), or lateral (outer) compartments of the [knee](

 /the-knee/

). It is powered by the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System, which allows for consistently reproducible precision in performing partial knee resurfacing.
&lt;p&gt;During the procedure, the diseased portion of the knee is resurfaced, sparing the patient’s healthy bone and surrounding tissue. An implant is then secured in the joint to allow the knee to move smoothly again. MAKOplasty® Partial Knee Resurfacing can:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Makoplasty Partial Knee Resurfacing</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 12:48:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://patients.stryker.com/knee-replacement/procedures/mako-robotic-arm-assisted"&gt;Partial knee replacement&lt;/a&gt; is a treatment option for people with early to mid-stage osteoarthritis (OA) that has not yet impacted their entire knee. Only the diseased portion of the knee is replaced, sparing healthy bone and the ligaments known as the ACL (anterior cruciate ligament) and PCL (posterior cruciate ligament).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="md-img-center text-center" style="margin-bottom:10px;" &gt;
 &lt;div class = "image-card-md col-center" style="border: 2px solid white"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-lg" alt="Partial knee replacement resurfaces only the damaged compartment of the knee while preserving the remaining healthy anatomy" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/makoplasty/partial_knee.png"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Partial knee replacement resurfaces only the damaged compartment of the knee while preserving the remaining healthy anatomy&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Makoplasty Total Hip Replacement</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-total-hip-replacement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 12:44:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-total-hip-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;MAKOplasty® &lt;a href="https://patients.stryker.com/hip-replacement/procedures/mako-robotic-arm-assisted"&gt;Total Hip Replacement&lt;/a&gt; is powered by the RIO® Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System. It is indicated for adults who suffer from non-inflammatory or inflammatory degenerative joint disease. The RIO® robotic arm advanced technology allows surgeons to achieve a new level of accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="who-is-a-candidate-for-makoplasty"&gt;Who is a Candidate for MAKOplasty®?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
If your symptoms aren’t responding to non-surgical solutions, or your pain can no longer be controlled by medication, you may be a candidate for MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Total Hip Replacement.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-candidate-for-makoplasty-total-hip-replacement-may-experience-the-following"&gt;A candidate for MAKOplasty® Total Hip Replacement may experience the following:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Pain while putting weight on the affected hip
Limping to lessen the weight-bearing pressure on the affected hip
Pain that may radiate to the groin, lower back, or down the thigh to the knee
Hip pain or stiffness during walking or other impact activities
Failure to respond to non-surgical treatments or nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory medication.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-does-makoplasty-work"&gt;How does MAKOplasty® Work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
If your surgeon determines that you are a good candidate for the MAKOplasty&amp;reg; procedure, a CT Scan will be taken of your hip one to two weeks prior to surgery. This is used to create a patient specific 3-D model. A surgical plan is then created for the placement and alignment of the implants before surgery.
&lt;p&gt;During surgery, the robotic arm guides the surgeon in preparing the socket in the pelvis and positions the impants optimally. Real-time information and images allow your surgeon to know and control accurate implant placement, which can be difficult to achieve using traditional surgical techniques without a robotic arm.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic (RIO) System</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/robotic-arm-interactive-orthopedic-system-rio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 12:37:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/robotic-arm-interactive-orthopedic-system-rio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The RIO® Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System features three dimensional pre-surgical planning. During surgery, the RIO® provides the surgeon with real-time visual, tactile and auditory feedback to facilitate optimal joint resurfacing and implant positioning. It is this optimal placement that can result in more natural knee motion following surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rio-features"&gt;RIO® Features:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Accurately plan implant size, orientation and alignment utilizing CT-derived 3-D modeling
Enabling the pre-resection capture of patient-specific kinematic tracking through full flexion and extension
Real-time intra-operative adjustments for correct knee kinematics and soft-tissue balance
Minimally invasive and bone sparing, with minimal tissue trauma for faster recovery
&lt;div class="md-img-center text-center"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-lg drop-shadow" alt="Rio Makoplasty" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/makoplasty/rio-makoplasty.jpg"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>