<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NewTech on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/tags/newtech/</link><description>Recent content in NewTech on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 22:40:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/tags/newtech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MAKOplasty</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 22:40:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-makoplasty"&gt;What is MAKOplasty®?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MAKOplasty® Partial Knee Resurfacing and MAKOplasty® Total Hip Replacement are
enabled by the surgeon controlled RIO® robotic arm system, offering increased accuracy to
optimize surgical results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing"&gt;MAKOplasty® Partial Knee Resurfacing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://patients.stryker.com/knee-replacement/options/mako-robotic-arm-assisted-partial-knee"&gt;Partial Knee Replacement&lt;/a&gt; is a treatment option for adults living with early-to mid-stage
osteoarthritis (OA) that has not progressed to all three compartments of the knee.
MAKOplasty® Partial Knee Resurfacing is an advanced treatment option. It is powered
by the RIO® Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System, which allows the surgeon to
perform surgery accurately through a smaller incision as compared to manual procedures.
By selectively targeting the part of the knee damaged by OA, surgeons can resurface the
knee while sparing the healthy bone and ligaments surrounding it. Partial knee resurfacing may be done unicompartmentally (when only one area of the joint needs resurfacing) or bicompartmentally (when two areas of the joint need to be resurfaced). Both options maintain the surrounding healthy bone and ligaments, unlike total knee replacements.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ACL Repair</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/acl-repair/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 23:11:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/acl-repair/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;ACL Repair is a revolutionary technique that allows patients to return to function sooner following surgery. Dr. Myers employs the use of a synthetic graft to strengthen the ACL and protect it during the recovery, improving patient outcomes and reducing the chances of re-injury.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-an-acl-what-happens-when-its-injured"&gt;What is an ACL? What happens when it&amp;rsquo;s injured?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr style="margin-bottom:20px;"&gt;
&lt;div class="row weak-center"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-sm-7" style="margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;
 The anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) is a piece of elastic tissue within your knee joint that provides stability to your knee, especially during back-and-forth and rotational movements. Damage to the ACL is one of the most common injuries in sports medicine, especially in athletes that participate in fast-paced sports like soccer, football, and basketball. Patients typically describe the moment of injury as a “popping” sensation within their knee, or a sudden feeling of instability. When the damaged ACL goes untreated, the knee may experience decreased stability and a feeling of “giving out” during certain movements. Injury to the ACL, depending on the severity, may require surgical intervention to fix.
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-sm-5 no-gutters" style="margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;
 &lt;div class="md-img-center text-center" style="margin-bottom:10px;" &gt;
 &lt;div class = "image-card-md col-center" style="border: 2px solid white"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-lg" alt="ACL tear" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/acl-repair/ACL_Tear.gif"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;ACL tear&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PRP Injections</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/prp-injections/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 23:11:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/prp-injections/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Platelet-Rich Plasma (PRP) injections are a new technology that uses the natural healing factors in blood to treat chronic injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PRP injections are most commonly used for tendinitis and chronic injuries such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tennis/Golfer’s Elbow aka Lateral/Medial Epicondylitis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achilles Tendinitis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plantar Fasciitis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chronic Hamstring Strains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runner’s Knee aka Patellar Tendinitis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Osteoarthritis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other uses can be discussed with the physician as indicated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the use of Platelet-Rich Plasma to treat osteoarthritis is experimental in nature and its effectiveness is still being studied.
Links to recent studies on the topic are included on this page if you would like to know more. Your physician will be able to make a recommendation based on your condition to determine if PRP is right for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>