<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured Procedures on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured Procedures on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 08:58:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DonJoy UltraSling Quadrant</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/shoulder-sling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:44:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/shoulder-sling/</guid>
      <description>The Donjoy Ultrasling Quadrant is a state of the art shoulder brace designed to stabilize the upper limb after shoulder surgery. The brace was designed by Dr. Myers for the comfort and rehabilitation of his patients. This is one of the many innovations that Dr. Myers has contributed to the field of orthopaedic surgery. 3 years in development, the Ultrasling Quadrant has many advantages over the prior shoulder immobilizers.
    Patient comfort - The Ultrasling Quadrant stabilizes the arm by supporting its weight on the hip as well as suspending it from the opposite shoulder with a strap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACL Animation</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/acl-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:43:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/procedures/acl-animation/</guid>
      <description>The video below demonstrates the N8TIVE ACL reconstruction surgical process in the knee.

  A tissue graft is removed from the patient, typically a tendon from the hamstring. The graft is prepared with sutures and resized according to the size of the patient&amp;rsquo;s original ACL.
A pin is placed on the Anteromedial (AM) Bundle footprint on the femur, the site where the ACL used to be attached. This pin is used as a guide to drill two tunnels for the ACL graft, one anteromedial (AM) and one posterolateral (PL).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>