<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Knee on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/</link><description>Recent content in The Knee on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:52:43 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Symptoms of an ACL Tear</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:52:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/symptoms-of-an-acl-tear/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The anterior cruciate ligament, also known as the ACL, is one of the major ligaments within the knee joint. The ligament connects the femur and tibia bones, providing stability to the
knee and preventing over-bending and over-straightening. An ACL tear can refer to any injury caused to the
ligament, from a minor sprain to a true tear.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="md-img-center text-center"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-sm" alt="ACL Tear" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/the-knee/acl-tear.gif"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
ACL tears are one of the most common types of sports injuries, and are typically caused by motions that apply twisting forces on the knee such as pivoting one one foot or stopping suddenly. Sports like football or soccer that involve such motions along with physical contact are more prone to causing ACL tears. ACL tears can also be received from non-contact sports related 
injuries, like landing from a jump, running, pivoting, or overextending the knee joint.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="acl-tear-symptoms"&gt;ACL Tear Symptoms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Symptoms of an ACL tear will vary based on how severe the tear is and whether or not additional injuries were received alongside the original injury.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pain&lt;/strong&gt; – Sudden onset of severe knee pain is common with an ACL tear.
Injury onset typically begins with a sharp, stabbing pain on the outside and back of the knee, which over time may become
a throbbing ache. Movements like straightening or bending the knee will increase the amount of pain.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meniscus Tears</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:47:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/meniscus-tears/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The menisci are small, “C”-shaped pieces of cartilage that act as cushions for the knee
joint. Each knee has both a medial (inner, towards the midline of the body) and lateral (outer) meniscus, both sitting on top of the tibia (shin bone).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-does-a-meniscus-become-torn"&gt;How does a Meniscus Become Torn?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
A meniscus tear usually occurs during movements that forcefully rotate the knee while the 
knee is bearing weight, which results in the piece of cartilage being torn. If the foot is 
firmly planted and an athlete quickly twists or rotates the upper leg, a partial or total 
tear of the meniscus could occur. This is common in sports that require cutting and pivoting such as soccer or football .
&lt;div class="md-img-center text-center"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-sm" alt="Meniscus Tear" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/the-knee/meniscus-tear.gif"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="meniscus-tear-symptoms"&gt;Meniscus Tear Symptoms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
When a meniscus is injured or torn, mild to severe pain (especially when the knee is 
straightened) occurs depending on how big the tear is. When a torn meniscus fragment 
catches between the tibia and femur, severe pain is common. Swelling is also common at the 
time of injury, but may appear hours later as the joint tissue becomes inflamed. An audible 
click or pop is frequently heard when the meniscus is injured. The knee may also lock, or 
feel weak. Smaller meniscus tears may heal over time with no surgery required, although some 
meniscus injuries benefit from surgical repair.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="diagnosis-and-treatment-of-meniscus-tears"&gt;Diagnosis and Treatment of Meniscus Tears&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
When a diagnosing a possible meniscus tear, the physician takes a complete history and performs a 
physical examination of the patient. The extent of the injury is often possible to determine using physical exam techniques that involve manipulating the knee joint in different ways. Using these techniques, the physician looks for pops, clicks, or pain with certain movements that may suggest a meniscus tear.
&lt;p&gt;Treating meniscus tears depends on the extent and location of the tear. Symptoms of smaller tears that do not impede knee function may be resolved with simple short-term treatments. Strengthening the muscles surrounding the knee joint through phyiscal therapy and a short regimen of anti-inflammmatory drugs is typically sufficient to treat such tears.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Articular Cartilage Tear Information</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:44:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-articular-cartilage"&gt;What is articular cartilage?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Articular cartilage, also known as hyaline cartilage, is a very smooth yet hard material 
made up of the protein collagen. The cartilage is located on a bone’s articulating surfaces 
(surfaces of a bone that come in contact with other bones). It allows for the smooth 
interaction between two bones in joints such as the knee.
&lt;div class="md-img-center text-center"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-sm" alt="Articular Cartilage Tear" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/the-knee/knee-articular-cartilage.gif"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-does-articular-cartilage-get-injured"&gt;How does articular cartilage get injured?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Damage to the articular cartilage may occur as an isolated incident or may develop due to another knee injury. 
For example, ACL (anterior cruciate ligament) injuries are commonly associated with damage 
to the medial (inner) and lateral (outer) surfaces of the femur (thigh bone) or tibia (shin bone). 
Because the ACL's function is to provide stability to the knee during rotation, a torn or injured ACL is unable to prevent the knee from damaging itself due to over-rotation. 
If an ACL goes untreated, twisting movements can cause the articulating surfaces of the femur and tibia 
to collide, damaging the cartilage on each surface. 
Articular cartilage may also be damaged due to forceful impact to a joint, such as a football tackle. The excessive force may cause the joint to collapse, forcing bones to collide and resulting in damage to the cartilage surfaces. 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="articular-cartilage-regeneration-and-repair"&gt;Articular Cartilage Regeneration and Repair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Regeneration of articular cartilage is an ongoing area of study in the field of orthopaedics. 
While there are currently no methods of reliably regenerating cartilage, there do exist methods of treatment. 
The most common treatments seek to alleviate the symptoms of cartilage damage by repairing the surrounding area and preventing further damage to the cartilage surfaces. 
Some new medical procedures aim to “fill in the holes” of the damage caused, typically using the body's scarring response to fill the damaged holes with scar tissue. The repaired area resembles hyaline cartilage, but is not true cartilage. As a result, these treatments have the potential to delay or prevent further damage to the actual cartilage but results vary.
&lt;p&gt;While damage to the articular cartilage is not life threatening, it can significantly impact long-term quality of life. Pain, swelling of the joints, restriction on activties, and reduced mobility are common with articular cartilage damage. By repairing the
tissue after damaging the articular cartilage, these negative effects can be greatly reduced.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>