<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Insurance on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Insurance on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:07:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cigna</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/cigna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:16:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/cigna/</guid>
      <description>CIGNA is a global health service company, dedicated to helping people improve their health, well-being and security. We provide an integrated suite of health, life, accident, disability and other wellness benefits to groups and individuals, serving over 45 million people throughout the United States and around the world.
Dr. Myers accepts CIGNA as a form of health insurance.
Cigna Homepage
Information taken from cigna.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United Health Care</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/united-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 23:57:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/united-health-care/</guid>
      <description>UnitedHealthcare is an operating division of UnitedHealth Group, the largest single health carrier in the United States.
As a recognized leader in the health and well-being industry, United Health Care strives to:
 Improve the quality and effectiveness of health care for all Americans Enhance access to health benefits Create products and services that make health care more affordable Use technology to make the health care system easier to navigate  Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aetna</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/aetna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:17:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/aetna/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Myers accepts Aetna as a form of health insurance.
Aetna offers “offer a broad range of traditional and consumer-directed health insurance products and related services. These include medical, pharmacy, dental, behavioral health, group life, long-term care and disability plans and medical management capabilities. Our customers include employer groups, individuals, college students, part-time and hourly workers, health plans and government-sponsored plans.”
Dr. Myers accepts Aetna as a form of health insurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Cross Blue Shield</title>
      <link>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/blue-cross-blue-shield/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:08:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myerssportsmedicine.com/insurance/blue-cross-blue-shield/</guid>
      <description>One of the most trusted names in health coverage, Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Georgia has been providing quality health benefits to state residents for over 70 years.
Dr. Myers accepts Blue Cross Blue Shield as a form of health insurance.
Blue Cross Blue Shield Homepage
Blue Cross Blue Shield Georgia Homepage</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>