<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Staff Bios on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/</link><description>Recent content in Staff Bios on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 08:07:04 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ryan Klosterman</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ryan-ingraffia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 08:07:04 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ryan-ingraffia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ryan graduated from Kennesaw State University in 2013 with a bachelor’s degree in Exercise and
Health Science with an interest in Physical Therapy. She then went on to Lanier Technical
College to complete the PT Assistant program and graduated in May 2016. Ryan has orthopedic
experience specializing interest in sports medicine, aquatic therapy, and balance retraining.
Ryan is now PT Assistant to Dr. Ross Brakeville.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jenna Hagan, MS, LAT, ATC, OTC, Practice Manager</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/jenna-williams/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 23:28:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/jenna-williams/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Jenna is from Columbus, Ohio and graduated in 2010 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Athletic Training with a minor in Health Science, from Marietta College in Marietta, Ohio. While attending Marietta College, she also played for their Division III soccer team. As she was working towards her degree, she covered several Division III sports including football, track and field, soccer, softball and women’s basketball. Jenna obtained her NATABOC certification and state licensure for athletic training in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amy Prall, MS, LAT, ATC</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/amy-prall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/amy-prall/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amy Prall is the Practice Manager for Myers Sports Medicine Orthopaedic Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy grew up in Cary, North Carolina before moving to Cleveland, TN to attend Lee University.
She graduated in 2012 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Athletic Training. She also
obtained her NATABOC certification and state licensure for athletic training in the same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Amy went on to earn her Master of Science degree in Sports Medicine from Georgia
State University in Atlanta, Georgia. While attending GSU, she worked at Kennesaw State
University as their Graduate Assistant Athletic Trainer for the Division I softball team. After
graduating in 2014, Amy was hired as a full time Assistant Athletic Trainer at KSU. Over the
next 8 years, Amy worked directly with the women’s basketball, cheerleading, men’s tennis,
women’s tennis, and volleyball programs at KSU.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ben Maggard, BS, EMT</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ben-maggard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/ben-maggard/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ben graduated from Auburn University Honors Program in 2023, earning his B.S. in Biomedical Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to his work at our clinic since graduation, he works part-time as an EMT for Metro Atlanta Ambulance Services and as an EMT instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His areas of interest include volunteering to address food insecurity around Atlanta, building computers, and golfing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bre-anne Naughton, MHA</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/breanne-naughton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/breanne-naughton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Bre-anne Naughton is the Front Office Specialist handling all Physical Therapy matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2021, Bre-anne moved to Georgia from Virginia. She graduated in 2018 with a bachelor’s
degree in Health Services Management from Norfolk State University and with her master’s
degree in Healthcare Administration from George Mason University in 2021. She brings seven
years of medical office and four years of medical billing experience to the practice. She believes
that healthcare should be pleasant for all stakeholders and is determined to provide exceptional
service to her community.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Caroline Rodgers, PA-C</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/caroline-rodgers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/caroline-rodgers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Caroline Rodgers is a Physical Assistant (PA-C) treating patients in our office Monday-Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caroline is from Woodstock, GA. She earned her undergraduate degree from the University of Georgia where she competed all four years on the Varsity Women’s Soccer Team. After her time at UGA, Caroline completed her medical training at Mercer University’s Physician Assistant Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caroline’s medical interests include knee and shoulder injuries and regenerative medicine. Caroline lives in Marietta with her husband and two goldendoodles. She enjoys spending time outdoors, being with her family, and is an Atlanta Braves fan.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kate Stanchev, CSA</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/kate-stanchev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/kate-stanchev/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Kate is a CSA (certified surgical assistant) that has over ten years of experience in orthopedics and additional specialties. She graduated from Chattahoochee Technical College with her certification in Surgery Technology and then continued to Meridian Institute of Surgical Assisting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has been assisting Dr. Myers in the operating room since 2014 and is now working alongside him in clinic. When she is not assisting in treating patients, she enjoys spending time with her husband and fur baby, reading, podcasting and working on her next published novel.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Michael Mcgrane</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/michael-mcgrane/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Michael McGrane served four years active duty in The U.S. Army. During his service, he trained at The Academy of Health Science, FT Sam Huston, Texas and was assigned to medical company Martin Army Hospital, FT Benning, GA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon returning to civilian life, Michael was employed at The Hughston Orthopaedic and Sports Medicine Clinic and remained there for over twelve years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early nineties, he left Columbus and began working the commercial side of radiology. During this time, he serviced film processors for X-ray of Georgia and later, Diagnostic Imaging Inc. where he was awarded the Eagle Award which is only given once a year to the best engineer in the nationwide company.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Molly Myers</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/molly-myers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/molly-myers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Molly Myers graduated from Virginia Tech in 1995 with a Bachelor of Science degree in
Chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After graduation she began her career in medical research at Johns Hopkins School of
Medicine in Baltimore, Maryland studying nuclear envelope formation. Upon moving to
Boston, Massachusetts in 1996 she continued her career at the Dana Farber Cancer
Institute where she worked in the field of breast cancer research. Leaving academic
research in 2000 she joined the Molecular and Cellular Oncology group at Millennium
Pharmaceuticals with a focus on prostate cancer research.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stacy Lee</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/stacy-lee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/staff-bios/stacy-lee/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Stacy relocated from Oregon where she gained extensive experience working as a medical office coordinator for over 10 years. She has received many outstanding patient service awards over the years and enjoys building close relationships with her patients. She and her husband currently live in Acworth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>