<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MAKOplasty on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title>
    <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MAKOplasty on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 22:40:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQs about Makoplasty</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/faqs-about-makoplasty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:02:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/faqs-about-makoplasty/</guid>
      <description>What is MAKOplasty&amp;reg;?  MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Partial Knee Resurfacing is an innovative treatment option for adults living with early to midstage OA in the medial (inner), patellofemoral (top), or lateral (outer) compartments of the knee. It is powered by the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System, which allows for consistently reproducible precision in performing partial knee resurfacing.
During the procedure, the diseased portion of the knee is resurfaced, sparing the patient’s healthy bone and surrounding tissue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makoplasty Partial Knee Resurfacing</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 12:48:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-partial-knee-resurfacing/</guid>
      <description>Partial knee replacement is a treatment option for people with early to mid-stage osteoarthritis (OA) that has not yet impacted their entire knee. Only the diseased portion of the knee is replaced, sparing healthy bone and the ligaments known as the ACL (anterior cruciate ligament) and PCL (posterior cruciate ligament).
Partial knee replacement resurfaces only the damaged compartment of the knee while preserving the remaining healthy anatomy
  MAKOplasty Partial Knee Resurfacing is an advanced partial knee surgery performed with the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makoplasty Total Hip Replacement</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-total-hip-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 12:44:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/makoplasty-total-hip-replacement/</guid>
      <description>MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Total Hip Replacement is powered by the RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System. It is indicated for adults who suffer from non-inflammatory or inflammatory degenerative joint disease. The RIO&amp;reg; robotic arm advanced technology allows surgeons to achieve a new level of accuracy.

Who is a Candidate for MAKOplasty&amp;reg;?  If your symptoms aren’t responding to non-surgical solutions, or your pain can no longer be controlled by medication, you may be a candidate for MAKOplasty&amp;reg; Total Hip Replacement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic (RIO) System</title>
      <link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/robotic-arm-interactive-orthopedic-system-rio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 12:37:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/makoplasty/robotic-arm-interactive-orthopedic-system-rio/</guid>
      <description>The RIO&amp;reg; Robotic Arm Interactive Orthopedic System features three dimensional pre-surgical planning. During surgery, the RIO&amp;reg; provides the surgeon with real-time visual, tactile and auditory feedback to facilitate optimal joint resurfacing and implant positioning. It is this optimal placement that can result in more natural knee motion following surgery.

RIO&amp;reg; Features:  Accurately plan implant size, orientation and alignment utilizing CT-derived 3-D modeling Enabling the pre-resection capture of patient-specific kinematic tracking through full flexion and extension Real-time intra-operative adjustments for correct knee kinematics and soft-tissue balance Minimally invasive and bone sparing, with minimal tissue trauma for faster recovery</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>