<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Edu on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/tags/edu/</link><description>Recent content in Edu on Myers Sports Medicine &amp; Orthopaedic Center</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:56:16 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/tags/edu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Shoulder</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:56:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/</guid><description>&lt;img class="md-img-left edu-img" alt="Shoulder" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/the-shoulder/shoulder.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many patients enter our office complaining of shoulder pain, suggesting that they have torn their rotator cuff. In actuality, very few patients have a true &lt;a href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/symptoms-of-a-rotator-cuff-tear/"&gt;Rotator Cuff Tear&lt;/a&gt;. There are several etiologies to shoulder pain besides a torn rotator cuff; &lt;a href="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-shoulder/frozen-shoulder/"&gt;Adhesive Capsulitis
(frozen shoulder&lt;/a&gt;), Subacromial Bursitis, Tendinitis, Glenohumeral Instability,
Chondrocalcinosis, Osteoarthritis, Gout, Lyme arthritis, and Ganglion Cysts are but a few possible causes of shoulder pain. When diagnosing shoulder pain, it is important to consider the method of injury as well as patient age and lifestyle to determine a patient&amp;rsquo;s actual condition.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Knee</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:41:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In human anatomy, the knee is the lower extremity joint connecting the femur and the tibia.
Tthe knee supports nearly the entire weight of the body, and as a result it is prone to both acute injuries like ligament tears and chronic injuries such as osteoarthritis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="md-img-center text-center"&gt;
 &lt;img class="edu-img-sm" alt="The Knee" src="https://myerssportsmedicine.com/images/the-knee/knee.jpg"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="function-of-the-knee"&gt;Function Of The Knee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
The knee functions as a living, self-maintaining, biologic transmission, designed to accept and transfer biomechanical loads between the femur, tibia, patella, and 
fibula. In this analogy, the ligaments represent non-rigid adaptable sensate linkages, used to hold everything together within 
the biologic transmission. [Articular cartilage](https://myerssportsmedicine.com/the-knee/articular-cartilage-tear-information/) acts as bearing surfaces, and the menisci 
as mobile bearings, smoothing out interactions between all the moving parts. The muscles function as living cellular engines that power movement in the joint as well as brakes and damping systems to absorb loads.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id="knee-anatomy"&gt;Knee Anatomy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
The knee itself is actually comprised of two joints, known as the femoro-patellar and femoro-tibial joints. 
&lt;p&gt;The femoro-patellar joint consists of the patella, or “kneecap”, a sesamoid bone
that sits within the tendon of the anterior (front) thigh muscle (m. quadriceps femoris), and the
patellar groove on the front of the femur through which it slides.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sports Medicine</title><link>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/sports-medicine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:28:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://myerssportsmedicine.com/sports-medicine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sports medicine specializes in the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of injuries and conditions related to
participation in sports and/or exercise, specifically the rotation or deformation of
joints or muscles caused by engaging in such physical activities.
While athletes and sports-related injuries are the primary focus of sports medicine physicians, any patients who wish to focus on maintaining an active lifestyle following treatment may benefit from seeing a sports medicine physician.
With a combination of exemplary care, state-of-the-art medical procedures, and in-house physical therapy, the team at Myers Sports Medicine and Orthoapedic Center is dedicated to helping patients maintain an active lifestyle during and following their treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>